在我们开始讨论机器人视觉之前，重新访问它将非常有用
Before we start talking about robotic vision, it’s going to be very useful just to revisit
机器人的一些基本原理，特别是机器人的定义。
some fundamentals of robots, and in particular, definitions of what a robot is.
对于那些参加过第一个在线课程的人，我们提出了这个定义
For those of you who participated in the first online course, we presented this definition
机器人是什么：它是一个可以感知，计划和行动的目标导向的机器。和
of what a robot is: It’s a goal-oriented machine that can sense, plan and act. And
重要的关键字在这里用红色突出显示。
the important keywords are highlighted here in red.
我们为机器人引入的一个更随意的定义是它是一台机器
A more casual definition that we introduced for a robot is that it’s a machine that
可以移动-或者移动自己或者可能是它的手-从A位移到B位。所以我们可以移动它的手
can move—either itself or perhaps its hand—from place A to place B. So we might move its hand
在A处拾取一个物体，并将其放在B处;或者它可能会移动整个
to pick up an object at place A, and put it down at place B; or it might move its entire
身体。它可能沿走廊中的A位走廊移动到B处
body. It might move along a corridor from place A in the corridor to place B in the
走廊。现在让我们看一下中的一些关键字
corridor. Let’s now look at some of the keywords in
第一个更详细的定义，其中一个关键概念是感知。
the first, more detailed definition, and one of the key concepts is sensing.
机器人从根本上讲是一种能够感知其环境的机器。各种各样的事情
A robot fundamentally is a machine that can sense its environment. The sorts of things
它可能想要感知的是：它需要操作的对象在哪里-在哪里
that it might want to sense is: where is the object that it needs to manipulate—where
是它需要接受的东西。它可能想要感知的另一件事是在哪里
is the thing that it needs to pick up. Another thing that it might want to sense is where
是机器人本身。走廊情况下的移动机器人;走廊里的下落是
is the robot itself. A mobile robot in a corridor situation; whereabouts in the corridor is
机器人？这是经典的'我在哪里？'移动机器人问题。
the robot? This is the classical ‘where am I?’ problem of mobile robotics.
机器人需要做的另一件事是计划。因此，从它的传感器，它知道它在哪里;
Another thing a robot needs to do is to plan. So from its sensors it knows where it is;
它知道它需要使用的东西在哪里;它有一个目标，一个东西
it knows where the things that it needs to work with are; it has got a goal, a thing
它想要实现。因此，它制定了从当前状态转移到何处的计划
that it wants to achieve. So it makes a plan of where to move from its current state to
它的目标国家。而这个过程的最后一部分就是随身携带
its goal state. And the final part of the process is to carry
一些行动。鉴于我有一个计划，现在我必须执行计划的步骤。
out some action. Given that I’ve got a plan, now I have to carry out the step of the plan.
我抓住了这个物体，或者我把自己从A地搬到了B处。
I grab the object or I move myself from place A to place B.